Mama Jack is a comedy film directed by Gray Hofmeyr.
Set in Cape Town, South Africa Mama Jack is the story of Jack
Theron, an ordinary person working on a film set.
However, his movie producer boss hates him and wants to
remove him from the production of the film.
In a bid to get rid of Jack, the producer spikes his drink with a drug at a glamorous
function, and before long Jack has got himself on the wrong side of the law.
While on the run, Jack turns to his friend, a make-up
artist, who turns him into "Mama Bolo".
Mama Bolo soon finds “herself” employed by the producer’s fiancée, Angela.
A series of deceptions and misunderstandings pile up and comic mayhem ensues with Jack
Theron becoming another character, Doctor Donald, a tramp from Scotland.
Jack Theron, Donald And Mama Bola, played by Leon Schuster.
Angela, played by Mary-Ann Barlow.
John D. Daragon, played by Lionel Newton.
Stanley, played by Jerry Mofokeng.
Shorty Dladla, played by Alfred Ntombela.
Mayoress, played by Shaleen Surtie-Richards.
Mama Jack is a 2005 South African comedy film by Leon Schuster.
It was directed by Gray Hofmeyr and distributed by Nu Metro.
It is one of Leon Schuster's most successful films.
The tone is lighthearted.